<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ebuka&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://daviper.github.io/</link>
    <description>Ebuka&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 14:06:12 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://daviper.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2 KDE GSoc</title>
      <link>https://daviper.github.io/post/week2kdesoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 14:06:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daviper.github.io/post/week2kdesoc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think i went down a rabbit hole&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided the next printer to make is QDir,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had to understand how things works,  making printers  feels like construction, its like you are given a set of tools, to produce an output.
The normal i take step to make a printer is to either dereference  d_ptr value or the d value ( they are usuallly included in QT types) , to use &lt;code&gt;ptype nameOfTheValue&lt;/code&gt;  but in both cases the output was an incomplete type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a little search, thanks to this &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/a/56313562&#34;&gt;answer&lt;/a&gt; from stackoverflow i was able to get the debugging symbols needed to view the internals of the QDir class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;next problem was getting the list of files in the directory show consistently, the files list only show up in gdb when either the method &lt;code&gt;QDir-&amp;gt;entryList()&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;QDir-&amp;gt;count()&lt;/code&gt; has been called previously, i then decided to call the entryList method when the printer is initialized that way the file list is always shown when QDir is called in GDB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the entire application would crash if the QDir has not yet been initialized in memory, because the method i am trying to call does not exist. since none of Qt classes have any fields named something like initialiized, could not find anything for sometime. I was able to figure out that most &lt;em&gt;advanced&lt;/em&gt; Qt classes usually have a field named QSharedData.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In QShareddata there is usually a field named ref that only has the value of one when the variable has been initialized, i was able to use that to make a condition statement to print the filelist of the directory if it is iniitalized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Pretty printer for QFileInfo was added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Pretty Printer for QstringRef was added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the repo can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://invent.kde.org/ebuka/gdb_printers&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next week would be Pointers Printer
Goodbye&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1 KDE Gsoc</title>
      <link>https://daviper.github.io/post/week1kdesoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 13:58:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daviper.github.io/post/week1kdesoc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first week was small steps were made,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;some printers for QT and KDE framework was already made,i imported those printers &lt;a href=&#34;https://invent.kde.org/kdevelop/kdevelop/-/tree/master/plugins/gdb/printers&#34;&gt;from here&lt;/a&gt;, also some from a qt merge request patch &lt;a href=&#34;https://codereview.qt-project.org/c/qt/qtbase/+/87052/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;removing any deprecated logic as the printers are quite old, some changes where made to the QListPrinter to fix the indexing and to account for typedefs like QStringList, QVariantList.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a problem of QListprinters not printing nested list,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;for example you have a declared a variable&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;QList&amp;lt;QList&amp;lt;QString&amp;gt;&amp;gt; nestedList = { {&amp;quot;one&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;two&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;three&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;four&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;aword&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;anotherone&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;yetanother&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;anoyetanother&amp;quot;}};&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the QListPrinter does not recognized this yet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new printer for QAtomic int is added&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the repo can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://invent.kde.org/ebuka/gdb_printers&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
Update by next week&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
